

Senior .NET Developer with 12 years experience



Current Designation: UI Developer Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less Current Company: Horizine Consulting Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mysore, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: C#,C#.Net,WCF,MVC,ASP.Net,LINQ,Entity Framework,Ajax,Web Services,SQL Server,NHibernate,ASP.Net MVC, JSON, Rest, OOPS, Design Patterns, JQuery, Javascript, Object Oriented Design, Multithreading, XML, TDD, Windows

Services, .NET Remoting, ADO. Net, MSMQ

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

Experience in C#.net, asp.net, WCF, MVC, Multithreading, SQL-Server, T-SQL, Windows Services, bootstrap.

Expertise working with AJAX, Json, JQuery, AngularJS, ExtJS, OOPS, Entity Framework, C# Generics.

Experience in Crystal Report and SSRS, Database design.

Experience in Payment gateway integration, Tortoise svn, Ankh svn, VSS, ClearCase, TFS, GIT

Experience in Google maps API and telerik, infragistics tools, NServiceBus, RabbitMQ

Experience in WCF Extensibility, Enterprise library, Dependency injection, MEF, Fluent validation, Unity.

Work Experience

Horizine Consulting as UI Developer

May 2020 to Till Date

Horigine Consulting as Senior UI Developer

May 2020 to May 2020

NTT DATA as Senior Software Developer

Jan 2019 to Oct 2019

- Coding, Design & Development. Implemented solid principles & Design patterns
- Consult & Coordinate with team for support related issues.

Projects: CHPW HealthGen (Medicare)

Technologies: Asp.net 5, C#.net, MVC and KnockoutJS, Windows Services, json, Jquery, Ajax, WebApi, SQL Server 2016, XML, XSLT

VITEOS CAPITAL MARKET as Module Lead

Apr 2018 to Jan 2019

- Generation of Windows Services based financial reports.
- UI Coding and Design with WebApi and MVC. Large Pdf conversions

Projects: Collateral, Treasury, MOS

Technologies: Asp.net 5, C#.net, MVC and AngularJS, Windows Services, json, Jquery, Ajax, WebApi, StructureMap, RabbitMq, SQL Server 2016, NHibernate

UST Global as System Analyst

Dec 2015 to Apr 2018

- On-the-Fly generation of product catalog details using sophisticated Scheduler Api.
- Sending/Receiving messages using Distributed Messaging systems.

Projects: B2B, Channel Engineering, Catalog Management

Technologies: Asp.net 5, C#.net, MVC and AngularJS, Windows Services, json, Jquery, Ajax, WebApi, StructureMap,

NServiceBus, RabbitMq, SQL Server 2016, Moq, EntityFramework

Education

UG: B.B.A/ B.M.S (Management) from Madurai Kamaraj University, Madurai in 2000

PG: MCA (Computers) from K.L.N College of Engineering ,Madurai in 2005

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C, C++, C#, VB, VC++,			
JAVASCRIPT, VBSCRIPT, FLASH			
WINDOWS, DOS			
SQL Server, My-SQL, MS-Access			
HTML, ASP, ASP.NET, IIS			
AJAX, JSON, CSS, JQuery			
MVC, Angular, Knockout, Nhibernate			
C#.Net, WCF, REST, Windows Services			12 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Tamil	Expert			
Hindi	Beginner			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: SC

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time